<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A message from the Lord, to the Parliament of England. That you may all take warning, and be ye all forewarned, that you act not in the steps of your forefathers, whom the Lord hath cast out as an abominable thing, as he hath done all rulers in all ages and generations, which have sought themselves, and established laws in their own wills, whereby the just have suffered, and now do suffer: the people which the Lord hath chosen are trodden upon, and the powers of the earth have set themselves against the mighty power of the Lord in them. But now is the Lord arising to plead the cause of the just, and woe for ever to all Sions adversaries. / By him who is a lover of your souls, and a lover of Israels common-wealth, whom the Lord is returning out of captivity, to serve him in their own land in perfect freedom. Geo. Fox.</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1654</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 41 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A84796</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1863</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E812_2</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R202175</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99862568</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99862568</idno>
            <idno type="VID">114731</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A84796)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 114731)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 123:E812[2])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A message from the Lord, to the Parliament of England. That you may all take warning, and be ye all forewarned, that you act not in the steps of your forefathers, whom the Lord hath cast out as an abominable thing, as he hath done all rulers in all ages and generations, which have sought themselves, and established laws in their own wills, whereby the just have suffered, and now do suffer: the people which the Lord hath chosen are trodden upon, and the powers of the earth have set themselves against the mighty power of the Lord in them. But now is the Lord arising to plead the cause of the just, and woe for ever to all Sions adversaries. / By him who is a lover of your souls, and a lover of Israels common-wealth, whom the Lord is returning out of captivity, to serve him in their own land in perfect freedom. Geo. Fox.</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 12, [2] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year, 1654.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>The last leaf is blank.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "7ber [i.e. September]. 1,5:"; "ye Goose" after 'Geo. Fox.'.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Doctrines --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1649-1660.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:114731:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A Meſſage from the Lord, TO THE Parliament OF ENGLAND.</p>
            <p>That you may all take warning, and be ye all forewarned, that you act not in the ſteps of your forefathers, whom the Lord hath caſt out as an abominable thing, as he hath done all Rulers in all Ages and Generations, which have ſought themſelves, and eſtabliſhed Laws in their own wills, whereby the Juſt have ſuffered, and now do ſuffer: The people which the Lord hath choſen are trodden upon, and the Powers of the Earth have ſet themſelves againſt the mighty power of the Lord in them. But now is the Lord ariſing to plead the cauſe of the Juſt, and woe for ever to all <hi>Sions</hi> Adverſaries.</p>
            <q>
               <p>By him who is a Lover of your ſouls, and a Lover of Iſraels Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-wealth, whom the Lord is returning out of captivity, to ſerve him in their own Land in perfect freedom.</p>
               <bibl>GEO. FOX.</bibl>
            </q>
            <q>
               <p>And the Lord ſhall utterly deſtroy the tongue of the Egyptian Sea, and with his mighty wind ſhall ſhake his hand over the River, and ſhall ſmite it in the ſeven ſtreams, and make men go over dryſhod,</p>
               <bibl>Iſa. 11.15.</bibl>
            </q>
            <q>
               <p>And there ſhall be an High-way for the remnant of his people, which ſhall be left from <hi>Aſſyria,</hi> like as it was to Iſrael, in the day that he came up out of the Land of <hi>Egypt,</hi>
               </p>
               <bibl>ver. 16.</bibl>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed in the Year, 1654.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:114731:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:114731:2"/>
            <head>A MESSAGE From the Lord, TO THE PARLIAMENT OF ENGLAND.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He word of the living God to this Nation; to the light in you all I ſpeak, which Chriſt Jeſus hath enlightned withall; which light is the way to Chriſt Jeſus, the Saviour and the father of light: and this is the true light which doth enlighten every one that comes into the world, which ſhews you ſin and evil, and your evil deeds, and your own inventions, and imagi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations; which if you love this light, and in it walk up to Chriſt, from whence it comes, who is the way to the father, and ſo to ſtand in the counſel of God, and to receive the Law from God, which is perfect, according to that of God in every mans conſcience; this doth indure for ever: then you will all come to witneſs the Lord is our Law-giver, and come to witneſs the ſound wiſdom, which is from above, that with it you may know how to order and rule in the Creation the Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures; by which wiſdom all things were made, where no invention of the Heathen enters: Now if you do hate this light, and follow your own Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theniſh inventions, and the Laws and Cuſtoms of Kings and Queens which formerly have been enacted (to the light in all your conſciences I
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:114731:3"/>ſpeak) that with it you may ſee how the Lord hath hewen down many who have followed their own inventions and ways, for all that which hath been enacted and invented, Laws and Statutes, and Acts in that nature, contrary to the light, is for condemnation with the light eternally to you all: this is the word of the living God: to the light of Chriſt in you all I do ſpeak, which is one; if you love it, you all love one, and then you will be one in the light; and it will teach you how to pray, and how to watch; and it will exerciſe your conſciences towards God, and towards man, and enlighten your underſtandings, and inform them towards Chriſt, from whence the light doth come; and with it you may ſee him, who bears his go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment upon his ſhoulders; who will reign and rule, yea, and he doth reign and rule, thouſands do witneſs it: praiſe and honour to the Lord God of heaven and earth for ever, who gives dominion to his Sons and daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters with his mighty power, over the world; glory and honour be to him for ever, who is ſetting up his Kingdom and Throne over all Principalities and Powers of the earth: who is gathering up to himſelf with his light, from the four corners of the earth. Now to the light in all your conſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ences I ſpeak; you that are gathering together to ſit in Council, that with it you may be kept in the fear of the Lord, and your minds up to Chriſt, from whence it comes: Now if you do act contrary to the light which Chriſt Jeſus hath enlightned you withall in your conſciences, which never changeth, and make a profeſſion of Chriſts words; that doth hold up that which acts contrary to the light, which is to be condemned with the light: Therefore to the light in all your conſciences I do ſpeak, that with it you may all be kept low, and few words, and not haſty, and in the fear of the Lord; and watch with the light, that ye be not drawn from it, to act con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the light in your conſciences; for you that do, the terror of the Lord God will perſue you, and the ſword of the Lord God is againſt you, to hew you down, as it hath done them before you; which have taken counſel, but not of the Lord, and gathered together, but not by him; and ſo broken to pieces according to Scripture: Therefore the Lord God fear, and ab<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e in his will and counſel; <hi>I am the light of the world, and do enlighten every one that comes into the world,</hi> ſaith Chriſt: one he loves the light, and walks in it, and receives the light of life, and doth not ſtumble, and walks not in darkneſs; and the other that hates the light, his deeds are evil; and he will not bring his deeds to the light, becauſe he knows his deeds be evil with the light; and ſo he that doth the evil, hates the light, becauſe his deads be evil, and the light will reprove him; ſo when the condemnation comes upon him, and Judgement from God, which is according to the light, he knows the Judgement is juſt, one with the light againſt him that hates it, and acts contrary to it, whoſe deeds be evil; ſo he that hateth the light, he hath the light, and he knows his deeds to be evil with the light, which Chriſt Jeſus hath enlightned him withal. And this is the condemnation, the light, all that hate it, whoſe deeds be evil, and act contrary to it: Now all you dwelling in the light, and waiting in the light, to receive your Law from God, which is perfect, according to the light of God in every ones conſcience: then he that acts contrary to the light, the Law of God, which is perfect, ſlays him, and cuts him down,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:114731:3"/>and puts him to the death, which is perfect, according to that of God in every mans conſcience; which Law of God hath power and dominion over a man as long as he lives: <hi>But I through the Law, am dead to the Law;</hi> yet we witneſs the Law good in its place, and juſt upon the unjuſt, who act contrary to the juſt principle in them; and holy upon the unholy, whoſe minds go from the pure light of Chriſt in them, and act contrary to it, and perfect according to the light of Chriſt, takes hold upon that which acts contrary to it which is not perfect; and to you this is the word of the Lord God: he that Judges for God, reſpects no mans perſon, but judges him that doth, for he that doth, goes from the pure light of Chriſt in him, and defiles the fleſh, which light would keep his mind to God, and that which goes into the fleſh, which would have a gift, which blinds the eye, which is the light; the light of the body is the eye, and this eye being ſingle, the body is full of light: ſo all of you dwell in this light: I do you warn and charge, and command in the preſence of the living God, that with it all your minds may be kept up to Chriſt, from whence it comes; if not, this is your condemnation, the light: and remember you are warned in your life time, before deſtruction come upon you, who act contrary to the light; and to you all this is the word of the Lord God: And to you all that are friends of God, the word of the Lord God to you; to the light of God in all you I do ſpeak, that you may come to witneſs the meaſure of God; ſtand up for the truth, and be bold and valiant, that is it which never changeth: wait I charge you in the preſence of the living God, that you may be led with the ſpirit of God, up to God, and with it comprehend the world, that you may witneſs that which will never wither; you who err from the pure ſpirit of the Lord, <hi>Balaam</hi> is your way, your fruit withers: and in <hi>Cains</hi> way, from the command of God, which are wroth; ſuch their countenance falls; ſuch are murderers of the juſt, and ſlayers, and perſecuters: ſuch their fruit withers, who goes from the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand, and hath no habitation in the Lord, but are vagabonds and fugi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives, as <hi>Cain</hi> was; and ſuch as err from the pure ſpirit of the Lord within, ſuch ſpeak great ſwelling words, have mens perſons in admiration, becauſe of advantage; ſuch Teachers ſpeaks evil of dignity, and diſpiſe dominion, and ſuch defile the fleſh, and what they know they know naturally, who turn from the command, and erre from the ſpirit: whoſe fruit withers, who ſaith, that Hebrew, Greek, and Latine is the original: before <hi>Babell</hi> was, all the earth was of one language, and <hi>Nimrod</hi> the cunning hunter, before the Lord, which came out of curſed <hi>Hams</hi> ſtock, the beginner and builder of <hi>Babell,</hi> whom God confounded into many languages; and this ſay they is the original; who erred from the Spirit and the Command. And <hi>Pilate</hi> had this original Hebrew, Greek and Latine, which crucified Chriſt, and ſet over him: and ſuch are they which ſay ſo, who go in <hi>Cains</hi> way, envy, ſlay, and perſecute, and in the way of <hi>Balaam,</hi> for gifts and rewards, the wages of unrighteouſneſs, which what they know, they know naturally, who err from the ſpirit, and turn into the many languages; and what they knovv they know naturally, in thoſe things they corrupt them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, vvhich are the men ordained of old for this condemnation: And this is the condemnation, the light, ſaith Chriſt; and to you this is the vvord
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:114731:4"/>of the Lord God; And dwell in the light, I warn and charge you all in the preſence of the living God, that you may be made manifeſt to the light in all conſciences, which reſpects no mans perſon; he that doth, is convinced with the light, to be a Tranſgreſſor of the Law of God: And he that dwells in the light faithfull and juſt, holy, and good, hates cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>touſneſs, fearing the Lord, beareth not his ſword in vain, is a terror to all them that do evil, for he hates the light that doth evil; ſo his law is upon him that acts contrary to the light that judges for God: Thou ſhalt not rail, nor ſpeak evil upon the Rulers of the People, for that which doth, tranſgreſſes the Law of God, and acts contrary to the light of God, that ſpeak evil, and rail upon them which dwell in the light of Chriſt, which hath received the Law from God, which is according to the light of Chriſt in every mans conſcience; which Law is a terror to him that evil doth, for he acts contrary to the light, and with it he is condemned and judged, with the Law of God: and to the light in all your conſciences I ſpeak: when you are forming, and contriving, and fetching things up in your minds, and to bring things according to your own wills and purpoſe: there is a light in all your conſciences, which will ſhew you the folly, bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens, and cumbrances, and troubles of theſe things; and <hi>Martha</hi> cumbred with many things: Therefore to the light in you I ſpeak, the one thing you may come to witneſs, and with it ſit at Jeſus feet, and with it all the other muſt be condemned and judged eternally, as you may ſee the wither<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and fading of it paſt before you. And now you are coming together to ſit in Council, the Lord God fear, that you may ſee what you take in hand; to the light in all your conſciences I ſpeak: (If you act contrary to it, you will be cut down, the terror of the Lord God will be upon you:) that with it your minds may be guided up to him, and you come to witneſs that which ſhall never wither, nor ever change: who turneth from it, doth not ſtand in Gods Council, nor turn people from their evil ways, but doth protect and hold up that which God is againſt, and doth forbid, and hath forbidden in ages paſt; ſuch as profeſs themſelves to be Teachers, which he hath ſent, his Prophets, his Apoſtles, and his Son to cry againſt; ſuch Teachers are in <hi>England</hi> now, and are and have been holden up by ſuch Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſtrates, as profeſs themſelves to be Chriſtian Magiſtrates: ſuch Teachers they are, as go in <hi>Cains</hi> way, in envy, to ſlay the innocent and righteous blood, and in <hi>Balaams</hi> way, from the ſpirit of the living God, which re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceives gifts and rewards, the wages of unrighteouſneſs; and many have been with your Laws and Inventions, made to ſuffer, to give them means and Tythes, according to the firſt Prieſthood: And all this is out of Chriſts way, who is the way, and all his Miniſters way: and is to be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demned with the light, all ſuch be; to the light in all your conſciences I ſpeak, that with it you may come to know Chriſt, who is the Way; and <hi>Balaams</hi> way, and <hi>Cains</hi> way, which is for the ſword, woe and condemna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; take heed of propagating that which is curſed from God eternally; to the light in your conſciences I ſpeak: you are now warned in your life time. And ſuch Teachers are propagated and held up as Miniſters of the Goſpel, which our Lord Jeſus Chriſt cryed woe againſt, and with his light them we do ſee, and him witneſs; and do witneſs againſt ſuch as he
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:114731:4"/>cryed woe againſt, who are not in his way, nor in his command, but in the Scribes and Phariſees way and ſeats; chiefeſt ſeats in the Aſſemblies, ſtand praying in the Synagogues, called of men Maſter, which our Lord Jeſus Chriſt forbids: ſaying, <hi>Be not ye called of men Maſter, for you have one Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, oven Chriſt, and ye are all brethren.</hi> This Maſter we own, who hath conquered death, and the grave, and the priſon, and hell, and temptati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons; aſcended far above all Principalities and Powers, blotted out the hand-writing of Ordinances which was againſt us, who are in the ſpirit: And this is the Maſter, the one Maſter Chriſt Jeſus, and all are brethren who are here; but who are in the Fleſh, are in the hand-writing of Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances and Commands: but ſuch are out of the ſpirit, and they are not contrary to them; and ſuch Teachers as are here, are called of men Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, and yet profeſs Chriſt; but your cloak will not cover you, your nakedneſs and skirts are ſeen, with the eternal light of Chriſt, which com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prehends the world, which is the worlds condemnation: And ſuch take Tythes of the poor people, and cauſe them to be haled before Courts and Seſſions, which will not give it them, which witneſſeth the ſecond Prieſthood Jeſus Chriſt, and ſees that the firſt Prieſthood is changed, which took tythes; and the Law is changed alſo, which gave it them: ſo many do ſuffer the ſpoyling of their goods, with ſuch that have the name of Chriſtians, Magiſtrates, and Teachers, which ſay they are Jews, but are not; which are and were the Synagogue of Satan: for the Prieſts that took Tythes, had a Store-houſe, and the people were to bring their Tythes and fill it; and the ſtrangers, widows and fatherleſs, were to come within the Prieſts gates and be ſatisfied, and filled; and the Prieſt was to Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter it forth to them, that no beggar might be in Iſrael: And the Prieſt was to Miniſter it forth out of the Store-houſe, a figure of the everlaſting Prieſt, who Miniſters out of the everlaſting treaſury. Now ſee if you with your Law have a Store-houſe, which gives the Prieſts Tythes; and all the widows, ſtrangers, and fatherleſs come within the Prieſts gates, and he to Miniſter forth to them, that no beggar be in <hi>England,</hi> as was none to be in Iſrael: Let the firſt Covenant judge your practice and your Law, and Prieſts both, and ſhew your nakedneſs of it, which was a figure of him who was to come. If you ſhould have a Store-houſe, and put the peoples Tythes in with your Law, and the Prieſts Miniſter it forth to the ſtrangers, wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dows, and fatherleſs, and no beggar be in <hi>England,</hi> as no beggar was to be in Iſrael, then you might not own Chriſt Jeſus to be come in the Fleſh; but hold up the firſt Prieſthood, which all who witneſs Chriſt Jeſus to be come in the Fleſh, witneſs the change of it, as his Diſciples, Miniſters and Apoſtles did, who confeſſed Chriſt Jeſus the unchangable Prieſt, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nyed the changable: Therefore they ſuffered perſecution, ſtoning, ſtock<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, priſoning, buffeting, beating and reproaches, and ſhameful threat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nings, as which is in <hi>England</hi> at this time, by them which call themſelves Chriſtians, and whoſe goods are ſpoyled them which confeſs the unchang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, and deny the changable Prieſthood that takes Tythes. Now if you do ſay, give <hi>Caeſar</hi> his due, <hi>Caeſar</hi> ſhall have his due in his place; but this not to hold up the figure: And you that are <hi>Caeſars,</hi> are not of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of Chriſt, but againſt him: Now if you do ſay, Chriſt ſaith, <hi>You pay
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:114731:5"/>Tythe of Cummin, Mint, and Auniſe, theſe things ought you to have done:</hi> We ſay the ſame, they ought to have been done; but woe unto them, for they were blind, that ſtrained at a knat, and ſwallowed a Camel: as Chriſt ſaith, the weightier matters of the Law were neglected; as Faith, Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and Mercy: had they been in the faith, judgement and mercy, they would have ſeen Chriſt, the unchangable Prieſt, the end of Tythe of An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſe, Mint, and Cummin, which was afore Chriſt Jeſus came in the Fleſh; ſo he came and witneſſed the figures in their places; but when he was ſacri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crificed up, the Apoſtles preached him, the unchangable Prieſt, and ſaid the Prieſthood was changed, and the Law alſo, which were witneſſes of Chriſts Miniſters of the ſpirit, which ſaw the miniſtration of condemna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, which was glorious in its time and place, but the Miniſtry of the ſpirit exceeds in glory, and herein is a deſtruction; and to you this is the word of the Lord: And ſuch Teachers are held up, and have been held up, as act contrary to the light of Chriſt, with ſuch as act contrary to the light of Chriſt; as are hirelings which the Lord ſent <hi>Micah</hi> to cry againſt, who was in the light, and ſuch Judges, who Judge for reward, and ſuch Teach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, as Teach for hire, and Prophets, as Propheſie for money, and Preach peace to the people; but ſuch as do not put into their mouths, they prepare war againſt them, and ſue them at the Law, and profeſs them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves Chriſtians, and Chriſtian Teachers, and Miniſters of the Goſpel. O cover your lips for ſhame, and ſtop your mouths for ever! <hi>Micah</hi> was in the light, who was ſent to cry out againſt ſuch things: and Chriſt Jeſus who is the light hath enlightned us with his light to ſee ſuch things now in <hi>England:</hi> ſtop your mouths for ever, making profeſſion of Chriſt and the Prophets, and act ſuch things as the Lord ſent his Prophet to cry againſt. And ſuch Teachers as act contrary to the light of Chriſt, are held up in the Nation, with the light of Chriſt Ieſus they are ſeen, which the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets in the light were ſent to cry againſt; which makes a prey upon the people, eats the fat, and cloaths with the wool, and kill them that were fed, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 34. <hi>And ſuch as ſeek for their gain from their quarter, greedy dumb dogs, which never have enough,</hi> which the Lord ſent <hi>Iſaiah</hi> to cry againſt, who was in the light; <hi>and ſuch as bear rule by their means,</hi> are held up, with many which are called Magiſtrates, and the people love to have it ſo, which the Prieſts, what they were to do, were to do freely, and not for hire; a figure of Ieſus Chriſt offering up himſelf freely: <hi>Shall not I viſit for theſe things, ſaith the Lord, ſhall not my ſoul be avenged on ſuch a Nation as this?</hi> O! a horrible and filthy thing is committed in the Land, Prieſts bear rule by their means, and people love to have it ſo; hath not the Lord vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſited here in <hi>England</hi> for theſe things? and he will viſit for ſuch things, and be avenged on ſuch a Nation as this; a fooliſh people which have eyes and ſee not, ears and hear not, hearts and cannot underſtand: <hi>Fear ye not me ſaith the Lord God, will ye not tremble at my preſence, who have placed the ſands for the bounds of the Sea, for a perpetual decree, that the waves thereof cannot paſs? O ye ſottiſh children, which hold up ſuch things, who are wiſe to do evil, but to do good, have no underſtanding, Ier.</hi> 4.5. And theſe are the Teachers, that ſaid the Steeple-houſe is the Church: and ſay the Letter is the light, the letter is the word, ſprinkling Infants,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:114731:5"/>Baptiſm, a little bread and wine the Communion, <hi>Matthew, Mark, Luke</hi> and <hi>Iohn</hi> is the Goſpel, Hebrew, Greek, and Latine is the original: Now with the light of Chriſt Ieſus, all this doctrine is ſeen, praiſed be God, to be falſe, and contrary to the Scriptures; they told us of mediate means, and a mediate call, and this we ſee was mediate, and what is mediate is natural; and the natu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral man receives not the things of God, and they which Miniſtred it forth, their call was mediate; this we do ſee with the immediate ſpirit of the Lord God: praiſed be the Lord God, and with it we do witneſs the ſpirit that gave forth the Scriptures, every one according to meaſure, which brings to witneſs the Scriptures, which ſaith, <hi>The Church is in God,</hi> 1 Theſ. 1.1. And the Baptiſm with one ſpirit, into one body, the ſpirit of the Lord, which we are all made to drink into; and the bread which we break, is the body of Chriſt, and the cup which we bleſs, in which is the Communion, is the blood of Chriſt, which waſheth from all ſin; and the word we come to witneſs, which was in the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning, before Hebrew, Greek, and Latine was, and <hi>Babell</hi> whom God con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>founded into many languages; ſo they that keep in the many languages, keep from Chriſt, for he redeems out of languages, tongues, kindreds, and Nations, and people, praiſed be the Lord God: and all who are here, are all one, and all who are in Tongues, kindreds, Nations and languages are in confuſion, not redeemed unto Chriſt; ſuch the Lord ſent his Prophets, and ſends his Prophets to Nations, to kindreds, languages, Tongues and People; as you may read in the Revelations, which now is fulfilled, and fulfilling in theſe days, praiſed be the Lord God for ever: And we do witneſs the everlaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Goſpel, the ſubſtance of <hi>Matthew, Mark, Luke,</hi> and <hi>Iohn,</hi> the ſubſtance of thoſe words; and they be the Miniſters of the Letter, which told us thoſe four books were the Goſpel: And we do witneſs God is the Fountain, who makes Miniſters by his will, as <hi>Paul</hi> was, as he often declares; and his call not of man, nor by man, but by the will of God: ſo <hi>Oxford</hi> and <hi>Cambridge,</hi> which is by man, and the will of man, makes Miniſters, with the eternal light of Chriſt, which was before <hi>Oxford</hi> and <hi>Cambridge,</hi> thoſe Fountains were: we do them comprehend and ſee, with it they muſt be condemned, who are bloody Perſecutors and Lyars, and no Miniſters of Chriſt Ieſus to the Lake: Therefore to the light in all your conſciences I ſpeak, which Chriſt Ieſus hath enlightned you withal, that with it you may come to read the Apoſtles words, who was in the light, and Chriſts words which proceeded from the light; and the Prophets words, which was in the light, which witneſſed Chriſt Ieſus, who was in the light. Now to the light in you all I ſpeak, which ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver changes; that with it you may come to ſee what the Apoſtles which were in the light, and Chriſt Ieſus the light; and the Prophets who were in the light, teſtified againſt: you may ſee with the light which never changes, not to hold it up; and to you this is the word of God, the curſed thing may be rooted out of the Land <hi>Baal,</hi> and his poſterity, which is curſed for ever, which is in that nature which acts contrary to the light. To the light in all your conſciences I ſpeak, that with it you may ſee many deceivers which be entered into the world; many Anti-chriſts which be entered into the world: thats the world which hates the light of Chriſt Ieſus, which he hath enlightned every one with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all; and thoſe are the Deceivers that are turned from this light, and thoſe the Anti-chriſts that are entred into the world, which are turned from this light:
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:114731:6"/>But its not poſſible that they ſhould deceive the Elect, which dwell in the light, which comprehends the world, and all the Deceivers and Anti-chriſts, and the world that hates it, and are turned from it: In this light doth the Saints, the Elect dwell, which condemns all the world which hates it, and the Antichriſts, and the Deceivers that are turned from it; for he is no Anti-chriſt, nor Deceiver that walks in the light which Chriſt Ieſus hath enlightned withal. Therfore to the light in you all I ſpeak, that with it you may come to witneſs the life that gave for<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>h the Scriptures, and with it come to have them opened again; then you need not have any private Interpreter, for they are of none; the pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate Interpreter is in the world, in his own will, among them which hates the light, which the Scripture came not by the will of man, but holy men of God ſpoke them forth, as they were moved by the holy Ghoſt; and the manifeſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſpirit is given to every man to profit withal. Now mind your pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fiting in the ſpirit, in grace, in wiſdom, in temperance, and in underſtanding; that you may come to witneſs the life that gave forth the Scriptures, which was before the Scripture was given forth; and with it they are read again, and cannot be read and underſtood without it which was before the Scripture was given forth: And all the Sects and Opinions are in that nature that hath the words declared from this life, but not this life; but are ſtrangers to the life of God, and the Covenant of Promiſe, but onely the words by hearſay in the world: there's many ways, many meanings, many ſenſes, many thoughts gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven upon thoſe words declared from the life, with ſuch as are ſtrangers from the life; all who be in the light and life are one, if they be ten thouſand; and with it all Sects, Opinions, larrs and Strifes are ſeen, comprehended, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demned; Images, and Image-makers, and falſe Worſhippers, who have the Letter, but not the life: there the devil brings Scripture, with the light all that is condemned, which leads into the worſhip of God, who is light, who is a ſpirit, and with the life all that is judged; and to you all this is the word of God, to the light in all your conſciences I ſpeak, which is your Teacher, lov<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing it, which is your condemnation, hating it; and walking in it, you ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive the light of life; and it will teach you lying in bed, and walking up and down, how you have ſpent your time, and do ſpend your time, from him who is a lover of your ſouls, and your eternal good: given forth from the ſpirit of the living God, for the cleanſing the Land of evil doers, and ſetting up the righteous Law, and eſtabliſhing righteouſneſs, and the perfect Law of God, which is according to that in every mans conſcience, which reſpects no mans perſon, but convinceth him that doth, as a Tranſgreſſor of the Law of God: So God Almighty direct you that fear him; and to you all I have cleared my conſcience, to the light of Chriſt Ieſus in you I ſpeak, which will condemn you that hate it: for this is the condemnation, the light, and to you this is the word of God.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>G.F.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:114731:6"/>
            <p>ALL the world is out of order, which hath not the life of the Law, and the life of the Goſpel; People, Magiſtrates and Miniſters, though they have the words of the Law, and the words of the Goſpel, Its the life that gave forth the Law, and the life of the Goſpel, that keeps in order the courſe of nature, and gives to every thing its reſt and peace, that hath been burthened; and gives every thing its due, and portion, that goes out of its place, which cumbers the ground, which ſtains the earth, that it doth not enjoy her reſt, nor her Sabbaths, nor yield her increaſe: But for <hi>Cams</hi> ſake, who is wroth, whoſe countenane falls, who is the vagabond, and fugitive; doth not abide in the command of God, who hath no habitation in the Lord; for his ſake the ground is curſed; who ſlayes the righteous blood, as it is written; and all workers of iniquity from Chriſt muſt de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part, which goes out of the command of God, are curſed from Chriſt, <hi>Go ye curſed,</hi> ſaith Chriſt.</p>
            <p>And all ye which would know the life, take heed to the light which Chriſt Ieſus hath enlightned you withall, and love it: It will lead you to Chriſt Ieſus the life, and all you that would know the way to ſalva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, ſtand ſtill in the light which comes from Chriſt, your ſtrength is to ſtand ſtill, and with the light you will ſee Chriſt Ieſus the Saviour, and there is your way to ſalvation; but you that hate the light which comes from Chriſt, and acts contrary to the light, all that ever you do invent and act in the changeable mind, now with it the light which ſhews you the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crets of your hearts, and your ſecret thoughts, and all the time you have ſpent, and all your actions you have done in time, with the light which comprehends time, and ſhews you all your actions done in time, contrary to the light, with the light you and all your actions, are to be condemned, which is eternal, and never changes, vvhich comprehends time, to you this is the vvord of God. Novv you have time prize it, this is the day of your viſitation, he that loves the light vvhich comes from Chriſt Ieſus, and witneſſes the unchangable Prieſt, Chriſt Ieſus is his way: But he that hates the light, hates Chriſt, and turns to the changeable Prieſts, <hi>Judes</hi> is his way to perdition, and not Chriſt; for when he forſook Chriſt, who was the way, he turned to the changable Prieſt; ſo Chriſt was not his way, nor is not their way now that do ſo, which takes Tythes.</p>
            <p>And all you that put repentance afar off, and live in profanneſs i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> your life time, ſafe and full; and ſay at what time ſoever a ſinner doth repent the Lord will be merciful, and bring the Scripture for you cloak, and deſpiſe that which is pure, which calls to repentance dayly, the light of Chriſt, for he calls ſinners to repentance; <hi>Eſaus</hi> end is yours, he ſought it with tears, and there was no place of repentance found: Therefore con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider, and harden not your hearts, while it is to day; hear his voyce which calls you to repentance, that you may receive refreſhing to your ſouls, and an entrance may be made t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the inheritance that never fades away; where nothing that is unclean ſhall enter, and to you this is the word of the Lord.</p>
            <p>The word of the Lord God to all you that puts your cleanſing off till af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter death in another world, and lives in pleaſures here in your life time,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:114731:7"/>faring ſumptuouſly every day, <hi>Dives</hi> like, his end is yours, mind what a cleanſing he had in the fire torment; and then it was ſaid to him, <hi>O man, remember thy life paſt, thou livedſt in eaſe and pleaſures:</hi> Therefore conſider, conſider, put not the evil day afar off, nor the good day afar off; for woe is unto ſuch, as you may read in the Scripture.</p>
            <p>Now you that do think we do deny Magiſtrates, and the Miniſters of Chriſt; ſuch we own, which receive freely from Chriſt, and freely do give, which are ſent into the world, to gather out of the world, up to Chriſt; and ſuch the Law was not made for, but for ſinners, and tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſſors; and that Law that takes hold upon ſuch, we own, which tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greſſes the pure light of God; and ſuch as are in the Lord we honour, for ſuch we know Iudge for God, and reſpect no mans perſon, but Iudge him that doth: and to you this is the word of the Lord.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>G. F.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <head>To all you Powers of the Earth.</head>
            <p>TO the light of Chriſt in your conſciences, which he hath enlightned you withal, to it I ſpeak; that in it you may ſee your ſelves, and what you do, and what you have done; and with it you may ſee to what condition the Scriptures were ſpoken, and with it you might have them opened.</p>
            <p>Chriſt ſaith unto the Phariſees, <hi>You pay Tythe of Mint, Anniſe, and cum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>min, and have omitted the weightier matters of the Law, Iudgement, Mercy, and Faith, theſe things ye ought to have done, and not to leave the other undone.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That was a time when Mint, Anniſe, and Cummin were to be paid, though Iudgement, Mercy, and Faith, weighter matters, were neglect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, for had they been in the faith, they would have ſeen him who was the end of all outward Figures and Ceremonies, and have been in the weigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tier matters of the Law; theſe being neglected, though they paid the Tythe of Mint, Anniſe, and Cummin, yet the woe was upon them; and that was a time when Chriſt ſpoke that to the Phariſees, which had the Figures, and told them theſe things ye ought to have done; for he came to fulfill them, and ſhewed forth and witneſſed every thing in its place. When Chriſt jeſus was ſacrificed upon the everlaſting offering, he blotted out the hand-writing of Ordinances, which are againſt us, which are in the ſpirit, and witneſs the everlaſting Prieſthood, and New Covenant, and triumph<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth over them; and the Apoſtle which preached Chriſts reſurrection, ſaid
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:114731:7"/>that the Prieſthood was changed, that had a command to receive Tythes, (and he preached the unchangable Prieſt) and the Law was changed alſo; ſo to you, all ye powers of the Earth, that give the Prieſts Tythes, and brings this Scripture, as Chriſt ſaith, <hi>Theſe things ye ought to have done;</hi> yeare the blind, and do not ſee nor believe Chriſt come in the fleſh, the everlaſting offering, who puts an end to theſe things; as the Priſthood that receives Tythes, and ſo they deny Chriſt come in the Fleſh, and do not witneſs Chriſt the unchangable Priſthood, but are in the ſtate of the Scribes and Phariſees, paying Tythe, and do not believe Chriſt, nor him to be come in the fleſh, as the Scribes and Phariſees did not.</p>
            <p>And anotehr Scripture you bring, as Chriſt ſaith, <hi>Whatſoever they bid you do, that do and obſerve, but they ſay and do not, therefore the woe was upon them; but do ye not after their works.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That was a time when Chriſt gave out thoſe words, before he was ſacri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficed up, who came to fulfil the Law, and not to break it; when he was ſacrificed up, and appeared to the Apoſtles again, he bid them preach the Goſpel, and the Apoſtles preached him, and he did not bid them go hear the Scribes and Phariſees, who had the form of <hi>Moſes</hi> Law, and did not live in the life of it, but bid them believe in Chriſt Ieſus, the end of the Law for by it no fleſh ſhall be juſtified, and therefore woe was upon them from Chriſt who was the life, ſo woe proceeds from him who is the them who have the form, and not the life; and ſo there Chriſt came to fulfill the Law, and not to break it.</p>
            <p>Another Scripture they bring, <hi>Some preach Chriſt of envy, ſome of conten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and ſtrife, ſome of good will, and in this the Apoſtle rejoyced, though their intention was to add affliction to his bonds.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>That was a time when few did believe that that was the Chriſt, that was before his name was ſpread abroad; ſo he rejoyced that envious men, and contentious men, and men of ſtrife, ſpread his name abroad, for few did believe that that was the Chriſt, as he himſelf had not: but when his name was ſpread abroad, and many had gotten the form, not having the power, from ſuch turn away, ſaith the Apoſtle, as you may read, 2 <hi>Tim.</hi> 3. <hi>which have the ſorm, not the power, which leads ſilly women captive, always learning, and never able <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> to come to the knowledge of the Truth;</hi> there he did not give freedom to ſuch, and bid them ſhun the occaſion of all con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tention, and ſtrife, and envying; there he did not give freedom for envi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous men, and contentious men to preach, but denyes them, though once he rejoyced in it, ſo to the light in you every one take heed, that with it you may ſee, to what conditions the Scriptures were ſpoken.</p>
            <p>And many are perſecuted, which ſay Chriſt is the light, with them that ſay the Letter is the light, that their ignorance might be ſeen, and their folly made manifeſt, to this I ſhall write, the chief Prieſts, Scribes and Phariſees had <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets words, which was declared from the light; and with the light they ſaw Chriſt, and with their words the chief Prieſts could tell where he ſhould be born, but knew not Chriſt the light. Now had the letter been the light, the Scribes and Phariſees which had it, would not have ſtumbled at him, who was the light and life of it; but they having the Letter declared from the light, and not the light, in their under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtandings, but hipt above, and ſo they knew him not, who was the light, but
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:114731:8"/>ſtumbled at the light, the Letter is not the light, but a declaration of the light.</p>
            <p>And again, many ſuffer perſecution for ſaying, God is the word, by them that ſay the Letter is the word; Now had the Letter been the word, the Scribes and Phariſees and chief Prieſts, which had the Letter, which came from the word of the Lord, and them which ſaw Chriſt, would have owned the word that became fleſh, which was the ſubſtance of that which <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets wrote, and ſpoke of, but they perſecuted and cru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cified the Lord of glory, which had the Letter, which was not the word that became fleſh; for had it been the word, they would have had it, but they that knew him, ſaid of them which crucified him, had they known him, they would not have crucified the Lord of life; therefore the letter is not the word, but a declaration of the word.</p>
            <p>Again, others ſuffer becauſe they do deny that Hebrew, Greek and Latine is the Original, that witneſs the word to be the original, by them that witneſs theſe many languages to be the original, for we which witneſs the word to be the original, by which all things were made, which was in the beginning, before many languages were; with the word we do ſee, that <hi>Pilate</hi> had the Hebrew Greek and Latine, which the Teachers of the world have told us to be the original, and <hi>Pilate</hi> crucified Chriſt, and ſo do they which have theſe originals, with the word before he was, we ſee both them and him, and that they are for the ſword, hammer and fire; and with the word we ſee that before <hi>Babel</hi> all the earth was of one language; and we do ſee that the Teachers of the world can go no far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, then ſince <hi>Babell</hi> was confounded in the many languages, and there we ſee they are in the many languages confuſed, which is confuſion; this we do ſee with the word before <hi>Babell</hi> was, praiſed be God; And we do ſee with the word, curſed <hi>Ham</hi> the father of <hi>Canaan, Nimrod</hi> the cunning hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter came out of his ſtock, was the beginner of the building of <hi>Babell,</hi> whom God confounded into many languages, which the Teachers of the world tell us is the original, and perſecute us becauſe we do not believe it; with the word we do ſee their foundation, their race, their beginning and their compaſs, with the foundation, which is the word, we ſee it, and with it they are threſhed, and with it they are chained, and with it they are ham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mered, for it is as a hammer, and with it they are cut, for it is as a ſword, and with it they are burnt, for it is as a fire, and unto you all this is the word of God; to that of God in your conſcience I ſpeak, mind the light of Chriſt in your conſcience, to be guided by it, to witneſs the word, and lead you out of <hi>Babylon,</hi> for it is come into remembrance before God, who will it confound.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:114731:8"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
